Guide to the E. L. Doctorow Papers 1931-2002 MSS 56 MSS 056
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II: Manuscripts
  - Subseries B: Short Fiction
    - Lives of the Poets (various drafts with corrections), undated (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Lives of the Poets (miscellaneous sections with corrections), undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Lives of the Poets (marked "#2 copy"), undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Lives of the Poets (setting copy fragment), undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Lives of the Poets (setting copy), undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Lives of the Poets (first pass galley masters), undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Lives of the Poets (second pass galley masters), undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Lives of the Poets (galleys), undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Lives of the Poets (repros), undated (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Lives of the Poets (xerox of repros), undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Lives of the Poets (repros and blues), undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Lives of the Poets (Polish translation), undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - "The Writer in the Family" (30-minute screenplay adapted by Mark Gilkes from the short story by E.L. Doctorow), undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript titled variously "Sarah Blumenthal's Conversations with Her Father," "Deconstruction," and "Boxcar. Camp. Museum."-Part 1, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript titled variously "Sarah Blumenthal's Conversations with Her Father," "Deconstruction," and "Boxcar.Camp. Museum."-Part 2, undated (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - "Pediatrician" or "Leo", undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "The Poet of Presidents Is the President of the Poets", undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Songs and Poems by E. L. Doctorow, undated (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - "The Songs of Billy Bathgate", undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - "Streetcar", undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Text for Eric Fischl, undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - "Versions of Mary and Joseph" or "The History of Christ", undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Untitled-"Livvy, age twelve, sits beside her books…", undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Subseries C
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "first draft"), undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "to be revised”), undated (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "Intro (rev)"), undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "1st revised), undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "2nd revised”), undated (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-marked "final revised”), undated (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (introduction-miscellaneous pages and drafts), undated (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (early version), undated (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (final draft), undated (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (draft with corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (draft with corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (draft with corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (notes, interviews, and correspondence), undated (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (collected essays, notes, and corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (collected essays, notes, and corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 29)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (collected essays, notes, and corrections), undated (Box 44, Folder 30)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (notes and title pages), undated (Box 44, Folder 31)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (collected essays and notes)-Part 1, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (collected essays and notes)-Part 2, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (setting copy), undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (galleys)-Part 1, undated (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (galleys)-Part 2, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (first pass galley masters)-Part 1, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (first pass galley masters)-Part 2, undated (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (second pass galley masters)-Part 1, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (second pass galley masters)-Part 2, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (repros)-Part 1, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (repros)-Part 2, undated (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (repros), undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (blues), undated (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Jack London, Hemingway, and the Constitution (unbound first edition), undated (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Piece for The New York Times, 1966, undated (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Piece regarding torture, 1976, undated (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "The Bomb Lives!" in Playboy, 1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "The New Poetry" in Harper's Weekly, 5/1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "False Documents," 11/1977, undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "Living in the House of Fiction" in The Nation, 4/1978, undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "My View" in Newsday, 8/6/1978, undated (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "The Language of Theater" in The Nation, 6/2/1979, undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Commencement Address-Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 6/3/1979, undated (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - "PEN Testifies" in the PEN American Center Newsletter, 5/1980, undated (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Book Review of The Scapegoat by Mary Lee Settle, Oct 1980 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Statement before the House Interior Appropriates Subcommittee and the House Appropriation Committee, Mar 25, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Remarks for writer's conference in Finland, Jun 1981 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Remarks for the Academy of American Achievement, Jul 2, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - "Who Will Paint America's Guernica?" in The Los Angeles Times, Jul 12, 1981 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Remarks at Bloomingdale's, Oct 7, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - "On the Brink of 1984" in Playboy, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Commencement Address-Sarah Lawrence College, May 27, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Commencement Address-Bronx High School of Arts and Science, Jun 27, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Remarks about the film Daniel, Jul 11, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "The Novelist Who Was Born Old" book review of An Amateur Laborer by Theodore Dreiser, Dec 4, 1983 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - "How Writers Write" for the University of Pittsburgh, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Commencement Address-Curry College, 1984 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Book Review of The Unbearable Lightness of Being by Milan Kundera, Apr 1984 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - "Conspiring with the Enemy: My Life in Publishing" [1985?], undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - "The Belief of Writers" from a lecture at the University of Michigan, Apr 1985 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Commencement Address-Kenyon College, May 19, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Remarks delivered at St. Peter's Church, Jun 4, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Remarks at Anti-Nuclear Rally, Aug 1985 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - "The Passion of Our Calling" in The New York Times, Aug 25, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Piece on The Adventures of Tom Sawyer in The New York Times, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - "Shultz and PEN" in The Nation, Jan 18, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - "The State of Mind of the Union" in The Nation, Mar 22, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - "Braver Than We Thought" book review of The Garden of Eden by Ernest Hemingway, May 18, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - Commencement Address-Pierson High School, Jun 1, 1986 (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - "Ultimate Discourse" in Esquire, Aug 1986 (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - "A Citizen Reads the Constitution", Sep 1986-Sep 1987 (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - "A Citizen Reads the Constitution" 9/1986-1987, Sep 1986-Sep 1987 (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - Remarks at the Seventh World Congress of the International Physicians for the Prevention of Nuclear War, Jun 1, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - Remarks for Poets and Writers dinner, Nov 1987 (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - "Tap-Dancer Among the Literati" in The New York Times, Oct 4, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - Book Reviews of The Letters of Jack London and American Dreamers, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - Remarks at the James Baldwin Memorial Convocation at City College, Apr 29, 1988 (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - Remarks for the Salman Rushdie rally, Feb 22, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - Remarks for the New York University Gallatin Association gathering, Apr 1989 (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - Remarks for Symphony Space, Apr 1989 (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - Commencement Speech-Brandeis University, May 1989 (Box 46, Folder 37)
    - Introductory Remarks for Governor Mario Cuomo, Sep 23, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - Toast for Robert L. Bernstein at the People for the American Way dinner, Nov 16, 1989 (Box 46, Folder 39)
    - Remarks to the American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters on receiving the William Dean Howell Medal for Fiction, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - Remarks for naturalized citizens, Mar 1990 (Box 46, Folder 41)
    - Preface to Plays and Other Writings by Árpád Göncz, May 1990 (Box 46, Folder 42)
    - Introduction to Call of the Wild by Jack London, Fall/1990 (Box 46, Folder 43)
    - Remarks upon acceptance of the PEN/Faulkner Award, May 12, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - "The Clear Sound of Honest Words" in The Washington Post, May 20, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 45)
    - "How to Save the City" in New York Magazine, Nov 1990 (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - Introduction to U.S.A. by John Dos Passos, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 47)
    - "An Open Letter to the President" in The Nation, Jan 1991 (Box 46, Folder 48)
    - "Administration Wars" in Mirabella, Mar 1991 (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - "Standards" in Harper's Magazine, Spring/1991 (Box 46, Folder 50)
    - Toast to Vaclav Havel at New York University, Oct 27, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 51)
    - "Art vs. the Uniculture" in The Nation, Nov 1991 (Box 46, Folder 52)
    - Testimony before the NEA Oversight Hearing, Oct 28, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 53)
    - "Nineteenth-Century New York" in Architectural Digest, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 54)
    - "Unnatural Acts" in American Theater, Jan 1992 (Box 46, Folder 55)
    - Commencement Speech-Southampton College, May 21, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 56)
    - An arts statement for Governor Clinton, Oct 8, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 57)
    - "The Character of Presidents" in The Nation, Nov 1992 (Box 46, Folder 58)
    - "On Inspiration", Sep 1993 (Box 46, Folder 59)
    - Book Review of Harriet Beecher Stowe: A Life by Joan D. Hendrick, Feb 13, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 60)
    - "Springs of the Imagination" in The Washington Post, Apr 17, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 61)
    - "After the Nightmare" in Sports Illustrated, Jun 25, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 62)
    - "Remarks by E. L. Doctorow on the occasion of the announcement to restore the Octagon House", Sep 2, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 63)
    - Samuel Clemens piece for The New Yorker, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 64)
    - "From Here to Death Row" in The New York Times, Jul 14, 1995 (Box 46, Folder 65)
    - "Mythologizing the Bomb" in The Nation, Aug 1995 (Box 46, Folder 66)
    - Foreword to Amerika by Franz Kafka, 1996 (Box 46, Folder 67)
    - Introduction to The Jazz Age by F. Scott Fitzgerald, Jun 1996 (Box 46, Folder 68)
    - Piece for Elaine Steinbeck, [1998] (Box 46, Folder 69)
    - "Has Starr Humiliated Us All?" in The New Yorker, Sep 28, 1998 (Box 46, Folder 70)
    - Introduction to The Adventures of Tom Sawyer by Mark Twain, 1999 (Box 46, Folder 71)
    - "Quick Cuts: The Novel Follows Film into a World of Fewer Words" in The New York Times, Mar 1999 (Box 46, Folder 72)
    - Address to New Rochelle School Board, undated (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Dedicating Walden Woods", undated (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Introductory Remarks for Margaret Atwood, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Introductory Remarks for Peter Carey and Mona Simpson, undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Introductory Remarks for John Cheever, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Introductory Remarks for Joao Ubaldo Riberiero and Moacyr Scliar, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Introductory Remarks for Annie Dillard, undated (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Kleist Introduction, undated (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Afterword for Arrowsmith by Sinclair Lewis, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Arthur piece for the Public Theater, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - "The Nineteenth Nervous Death of the Novel", undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Notes for Good Morning America, undated (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - "Notes on Hearing the Bible Read from Space", undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - "Other Jews", undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - "Politics of God", undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Remarks for Adolph Green's 80th Birthday, undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Remarks on Chekhov, undated (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Remarks on Clean Water Act, undated (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Remarks on Drinks Before Dinner, undated (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Remarks for Hamilton Fish fundraiser, undated (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - "Remarks on Hearing Poulenc's Sonata for Flute and Piano", undated (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Remarks on Wei Jingsheng, undated (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Remarks on John F. Kennedy, undated (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Remarks on Victor Navasky, undated (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Remarks on paperback books, undated (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Remarks on Ragtime, undated (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - Remarks on Mac Rosenthal, undated (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - Remarks on Stock Market, undated (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Remarks on Tolstoy, undated (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Remarks on The Waterworks, undated (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Remarks on James Wright, undated (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Suggestions for improvement of quality of life in Westchester County for The New York Times' Westchester section, undated (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - White House toast to Brazilian President, undated (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - Untitled-"Here's an eyewitness description…", undated (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Untitled-"Perhaps this afternoon we can…", undated (Box 47, Folder 35)
    - Untitled-"You may once or twice have asked…", undated (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified drafts of speeches, undated (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous collection of non-fiction fragments, undated (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Subseries D: Play
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 1, undated (Box 47, Folder 39)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 2, undated (Box 47, Folder 40)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 3, undated (Box 47, Folder 41)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 4, undated (Box 47, Folder 42)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 5, undated (Box 47, Folder 43)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (unidentified drafts and notes)-Part 6, undated (Box 47, Folder 44)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (incomplete draft with corrections), undated (Box 47, Folder 45)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (xerox copy with some edits), undated (Box 47, Folder 46)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (setting copy with corrections), undated (Box 47, Folder 47)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (proofs), undated (Box 47, Folder 48)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (second pass galley masters), undated (Box 47, Folder 49)
    - Drinks Before Dinner (blues), undated (Box 47, Folder 50)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous Notes and Fragments
    - Fragments including Lives of the Poets, Billy Bathgate, and other short works, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Short selections of various Doctorow novels (perhaps for readings?), undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous galley fragments, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (from file folder)-Part 1, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (from file folder)-Part 2, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (from file folder)-Part 3, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments (from file folder)-Part 4, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments, undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
- Oversize Series II: Manuscripts
  - Subseries A: Novels
    - The Book of Daniel- celophane wall chart with notes and plot, undated (Roll-storage 1)
    - The Book of Daniel (galleys with corrections), undated (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Loon Lake (first revised galleys), undated (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified translation (galleys), undated (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Subseries B: Short Fiction
    - "The Writer in the Family" (galleys for Cosmopolitan), undated (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Non-Fiction
    - Oversize Non-Fiction galleys with corrections, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)